Guide to the Jane Ellen Marcus Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Jane Ellen Marcus papers
circa 1977-2008
SC1173
Marcus, Jane Ellen.
5 Linear feet (3 cartons, 1 box)
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
This collection was given by Jane Marcus to Stanford University, Special Collections in August 2013.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical/Historical note
Jane Marcus first came to Stanford in 1977 as a temporary office assistant at the Stanford Linear Accelerator Center. After a year, she started graduate school, earning a doctoral degree in 1985 in administration and policy analysis, with a concentration on technology in education. Over her 31 years at Stanford, Marcus helped faculty integrate computers into their teaching and sustained a network for staff across campus as the cornerstone of the Team to Improve Productivity at Stanford (TIPS).
Marcus joined TIPS, which was formed in 1988 to advise on the development of business applications, in 1995. As the group's coordinator, Marcus was been responsible for convening the gatherings, facilitating discussions and publicizing TIPS and its mission through an e-mail list and word of mouth.
Marcus retired in 2008 as the IT Services account manager for the central administration offices of Student Affairs, Undergraduate Education, the Controller's Office and the Office of Development.
Scope and Contents
These files pertain to Marcus' contributions toward the development of many campus technology programs including Team to Improve Productivity at Stanford (TIPS), and her work to help faculty integrate computers into their teaching.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Academic Computing and Information Services; Stanford University. Information Technology Services; Stanford University. Team to Improve Productivity at Stanford (TIPS).; Education, Higher--Effect of technological innovations on.; Information services
Collection Contents
- OB analysis (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Online Bookshelf Baseline, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Online Bookshelf Cont., 1995 Aug (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Technology Planning, 1988-1999 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- TIPS & Delphi, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- VPUE (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "Technically Well-Managed Unit", 1999 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Technology publications, 1983-2011 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "Future Directions: Information Technology in Support of Scholarly and Administrative Activities." The Future of Computing at Stanford Report of the Task Force., 1981 January (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Mouse research (Box 1, Folder 10)
- The Tiro Project, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Stanford Computing Reports, circa 1980s (Box 1, Folder 12)
- General Stanford Policy on Computers, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Stanford Vice Provost for IT/CIO, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Strategic Planning (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Departmental Consulting (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Work Analyses, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Department Consulting (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Computer Resource Center (Box 1, Folder 19)
- SAIL, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- HumBio Project, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Developing Local Expertise, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Origins of Expert Partners, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Engelbart, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Three Year Plan for Information Resources, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- COST publications, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 26)
- HumBio Project, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Report of the Transition Team Information Technology Services Stanford University, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- From Luddite Mystification to Executive Control: The IBM TIRO Project at Stanford University, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Portrait of a Studen'ts Desk: Computing for Undergraduates at Stanford (Board of Trustees Guest Report), 1984 Oct 8 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- New Office Technologies: Cost Analysis, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Evaluating Text Processing Alternatives, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Avoiding a Tower of Babel: Stanford Initiatitves (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Mainframe History (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Computer Conference, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- News Clippings (Box 1, Folder 36)
- AISEC, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- ICA Paper, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Scientific Writing, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- NACUBO, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Final Reports, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Planning, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Complete Frequency Tables, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Focus Groups, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Data Reports Preliminary, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- CACIS, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Sustainable Stanford, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Clark, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Dean of Research, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Key Documents, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Research Data Center, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Survey to Assess Faculty Needs for Technology Infrastructure at Stanford, 2001; 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Woods Institute, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Web 2.0, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- ITSS Teaching/Research Support, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Strategic Planning, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Kiesler & Sproull, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- ITS Project Management, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- TIPS, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- TIPS 10-Year Anniversary, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- IEC-Zimbra Conversion, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Windows, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Zimbra, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Ergo, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Emeriti Faculty, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Security, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Class Accounts, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- TIPS Topics, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Leadership Development, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- TIPS Annual Survey, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- TIPS UMG, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- TIPS Wiki, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Working Group, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Work Anywhere, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Change, 1.0 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- L & IR, 1993; 1.0 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Req Report, 1.0 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Papers to Pursue, 1.0 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Library Futures, 1.0 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Paper Cost, 1.0 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Reports, 1.0 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Education - General, 1.0 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Higher Ed, 1.0 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Org. Comm., 1.0 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- References, 1.0 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Questionnaires, 1.0 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Blank Surveys, 1.0 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Development Opportunities, 1.0 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Electronic Mail, 1.0 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Online Bookshelf, 1.0 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- OBS Report, 1.0 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- TIPS Slides, 1.0 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Audiovisual Materials
  - 95AAHE-29 National Trends in the Uses of Information Technology: The Myth of Academic Productivity AAHE National Conference on Higer Education, 1995; 4.1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The Interactice Syllabus: A Resource-Based, Constructivist Approach to Learning, 2001; 4.2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - 95AAHE-42 A Society On-Line: The Challenge of Change AAHE National Conference on Higher Education, 1995; 4.3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Educom 9132 Tape 27 Evaluating Educational Technology In Field, 4.4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Educom 9132 Tape 50 Computing In The Humanities, 4.5; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - 9561 Cause 95 Tape 73 Effective Teaching & Learning Using Technology, 4.6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - 9561 Cause 95 Tape 47 Mainstream Use of Instructional Technology, 4.7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - 9650 Cause 96 Tape 48 1996 Cause Award - Self-Organizing Systems, 4.8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Measuring the Quality, Cost and Value of IT Services, 2001; 4.9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Educom 9132 Tape 21 Faculty & Electronically-Rendered Knowledge, 4.10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Synergy of Partnerships, 4.11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - TIPS, 4.12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - "The Virtual University" at Cal Poly San Luis Obispa, 1994 Oct 26; 4.13; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 4)